Well, there's lots to talk about,
حسنا.هناك الكثير لنتحدث عنه,
but I think I'm just going to play to start off.
لكني اظن اني سوف اقوم بالعزف لنبدأ.
(Music)
(موسيقى)
♫ When I wake up ♫
♫ عندما استيقظ ♫
♫ in the morning ♫
♫ في الصباح ♫
♫ I pour the coffee ♫
♫ اسكب القهوة ♫
♫ I read the paper ♫
♫ اقرأ الجريدة ♫
♫ And then I slowly ♫
♫ ثم ببطأ ♫
♫ and so softly ♫
♫ وبرقة شديدة ♫
♫ do the dishes ♫
♫ اغسل الاطباق ♫
♫ So feed the fishes ♫
♫ و أطعم الاسماك ♫
♫ You sing me happy birthday ♫
♫ و تغنين لي عيد ميلاد سعيد ♫
♫ Like it's gonna be ♫
♫ كما لو أنه سوف يكون ♫
♫ your last day ♫
♫ اخر يوم لك ♫
♫ here on Earth ♫
♫ في هذه الارض ♫
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
All right.
حسنا.
So, I wanted to do something special today.
اذا, اليوم اريد ان اقوم بعمل شيء مميز.
I want to debut a new song that I've been working on
اريد ان اظهر لأول مرة اغنية جديدة كنت اعمل على اعدادها
in the last five or six months.
خلال الستة اشهر الماضية.
And there's few things more thrilling
وهناك بعض الاشياء اكثر اثارة
than playing a song
من مجرد اداء اغنية
for the first time in front of an audience,
لاول مرة امام جمهور,
especially when it's half-finished.
خصوصا عندم تكون نصف مكتملة.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
I'm kind of hoping some conversations here
ارجو ان بعض المناقاشات هنا
might help me finish it.
ربما تساعدني على اكمالها.
Because it gets into all sorts
لانها تتداخل بأشكال مختلفة
of crazy realms.
من العوالم المجنونة.
And so this is basically a song
عموما هذه الاغنية
about loops,
عن الحلقات،
but not the kind of loops that I make up here.
لكنه ليس ذلك النوع من الحلقات الذي اقوم به هنا.
They're feedback loops.
انها حلقات اعادة التغذية.
And in the audio world
في عالم الصوت
that's when the microphone gets too close
عندما يكون الميكروفون قريبا جدا
to its sound source,
من مصدر الصوت،
and then it gets in this self-destructive loop
بالتالي يدخل في حلقة التدمير الذاتي
that creates a very unpleasant sound.
ذلك يخلق صوت مزعج جدا.
And I'm going to demonstrate for you.
وسأقوم بشرح ذلك لكم.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
I'm not going to hurt you. Don't worry.
لن اقوم بايذائكم. لا تقلقوا.
♫ This is a loop, feedback loop ♫
♫ هذه حلقة, حلقة اعادة تغذية ♫
♫ This is a -- (Feedback)
♫ هذه -- (اعادة تغذية)
All right. I don't know if that was necessary to demonstrate --
حسنا, لا اعلم اذا كان ذلك ضروريا للشرح--
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
-- but my point is it's the sound of self-destruction.
--لكن فكرتي هي صوت التدمير الذاتي.
And I've been thinking about
وكنت افكر حول
how that applies across a whole spectrum of realms,
كيف يمكن تطبيقها على جميع الاصعدة،
from, say, the ecological, okay.
ابتداء من ,لنقل, الصعيد البيئي, حسنا.
There seems to be a rule in nature
يبدو ان هناك قانون في الطبيعة
that if you get too close to where you came from,
انه عندما تقترب جدا من مصدر وجودك,
it gets ugly.
يصبح ذلك بشعا.
So like, you can't feed cows their own brains
مثلا , لا يمكنك اطعام البقر ادمغتها,
or you get mad cow disease,
والا سيكون هناك مرض جنون البقر,
and inbreeding and incest
وزواج المحارم وسفاح المحارم
and, let's see,
و, دعونا نفكر،
what's the other one?
ماهو الشيء الاخر؟
Biological -- there's autoimmune diseases,
علم الحياة -- هناك امراض ذاتية،
where the body attacks itself
حيث يقوم الجسم بالهجوم على نفسه
a little too overzealously
بحماسة شديدة نوعا ما
and destroys the host,
ويدمر الجسم الحاضن،
or the person.
او الشخص.
And then -- okay, this is where we get to the song --
ومن ثم-- حسنا, هكذا نحصل على الاغنية--
kind of bridges the gap to the emotional.
بناء جسور لتخطي الفجوة باتجاه العاطفة.
Because although I've used scientific terms
لانه بالرغم من انني استخدمت تعابير علمية
in songs,
في الاغاني
it's very difficult sometimes to make them lyrical.
في بعض الاحيان يصعب جدا جعلها غنائية.
And there's some things
وهناك بعض الاشياء
you just don't need to have in songs.
لا تريد وجودها في الاغاني.
So I'm trying to bridge this gap
وبالتالي انا احاول تخطي الفجوة
between this idea and this melody.
بين الفكرة واللحن.
And so, I don't know if you've ever had this,
ولذلك, لا اعلم اذا كنتم واجهتم مثل هذه الحالة،
but when I close my eyes sometimes
لكنني بعض الاحيان حين اغلق عيني
and try to sleep,
محاولا النوم،
I can't stop thinking about my own eyes.
لا اكف عن التفكير في عيوني.
And it's like your eyes
وهي مثل عيونكم
start straining to see themselves.
تحملق محاولة رؤية نفسها.
That's what it feels like to me.
هكذا اشعر بالامر.
It's not pleasant.
انه غير مفرح.
I'm sorry if I put that idea in your head.
انا اسف اذا كنت وضعت الفكرة في رؤسكم.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
It's impossible, of course, for your eyes to see themselves,
بالطبع انه من المستحيل على عينيك ان ترى نفسها،
but they seem to be trying.
لكنها يبدو انها تحاول.
So that's getting a little more closer to a personal experience.
وذلك يقترب اكثر من تجربة شخصية.
Or ears being able to hear themselves --
او الاذان تحاول سماع نفسها --
it's just impossible.
ذلك مستحيل:
That's the thing.
هذا هو بيت القصيد.
So, I've been working on this song
لذلك كنت اعمل على هذه الاغنية
that mentions these things
التي تتطرق لتلك الامور
and then also imagines
وايضا تتخيل
a person who's been so successful
اشخاص , تمكنو بنجاح
at defending themselves from heartbreak
من منع انفسهم من تحطيم قلوبهم
that they're left to do the deed themselves,
وقد صنعوا معروفا لانفسهم،
if that's possible.
اذا كان ذلك ممكنا.
And that's what the song is asking.
وهذا ما تتسآئل عنه هذه الاغنية.
All right.
حسنا.
It doesn't have a name yet.
ليس للاغنية اسم حتى الان.
(Music)
(موسيقى)
♫ Go ahead and congratulate yourself ♫
♫ استمر وهنئ نفسك ♫
♫ Give yourself a hand, the hand is your hand ♫
♫ صافح نفسك بيدك ♫
♫ And the eye that eyes itself is your eye ♫
♫ والعين التي تبصر نفسها هي عينك ♫
♫ And the ear that hears itself is near ♫
♫ والاذن التي تسمع نفسها قريبة ♫
♫ 'Cause it's your ear, oh oh ♫
♫ لانها اذنك, نعم نعم ♫
♫ You've done the impossible now ♫
♫ الان قد قمت بالمستحيل ♫
♫ Took yourself apart ♫
♫ جزأت نفسك ♫
♫ You made yourself invulnerable ♫
♫ اصبح من الصعب ايذاءك ♫
♫ No one can break your heart ♫
♫ لا احد يستطيع تحطيم قلبك ♫
♫ So you wear it out ♫
♫ لأنك انهكته ♫
♫ And you wring it out ♫
♫ ثم اعتصرته ♫
♫ And you wear it out ♫
♫ ثم انهكته ♫
♫ And you break it yourself ♫
♫ وحطمته بنفسك ♫
♫ Breaking your own, break it yourself ♫
♫ حطمت قلبك, حطمته بنفسك ♫
♫ Breaking your own ♫
♫ حطمت قلبك ♫
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
Thanks.
شكرا.
All right.
حسنا.
It's kind of cool. Songwriters can sort of get away with murder.
ذلك يبدو جيدا . كاتبوا الاغاني يمكنهم التنصل من جريمة قتل.
You can throw out crazy theories
يمكنهم ابتكار نظريات مجنونة
and not have to back it up with data
وليس عليهم دعمها بالبيانات
or graphs or research.
او الرسومات او الابحاث.
But, you know, I think reckless curiosity
لكنني اعتقد ان الفضول المتهور
would be what the world needs now,
هو ما يحتاجه العالم الان،
just a little bit.
فقط القليل من ذلك.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
I'm going to finish up with a song of mine
انا على وشك الانتهاء من احدى اغنياتي
called "Weather Systems."
تسمى " انظمة الطقس "
(Music)
(موسيقى)
♫ Quiet ♫
♫ اهدأ ♫
♫ Quiet down, she said ♫
ّ♫ قالت له اهدأ ♫
♫ Speak into the back of his head ♫
♫ تتحدث لمؤخرة رأسه ♫
♫ On the edge of the bed, I can see your blood flow ♫
♫ على حافة الفراش ,بامكاني رؤية انسياب دماءك ♫
♫ I can see your ♫
♫ يمكنني رؤية ♫
♫ cells grow ♫
♫ خلاياك تنمو ♫
♫ Hold still awhile ♫
♫ ابقى ساكنا للحظة ♫
♫ Don't spill the wine ♫
♫ لا تسكب النبيذ ♫
♫ I can see it all from here ♫
♫ بامكاني رؤية كل ذلك من مكاني ♫
♫ I can see ♫
♫ استطيع ان ارى ♫
♫ oh, I ♫
♫ نعم , نعم ♫
♫ weather systems ♫
♫ انظمة الطقس ♫
♫ of the world ♫
♫ الخاصة بالعالم ♫
♫ Some things you say ♫
♫ بعض الاشياء التي تقولها ♫
♫ are not for sale ♫
♫ ليست للبيع ♫
♫ I would hold it where ♫
♫ واود الاحتفاظ بها حيث ♫
♫ our free agents of some substance are ♫
♫ وكلاءنا المجانيين لبعض المواد ♫
♫ scared ♫
♫ مرتعبون ♫
♫ Hold still a while ♫
♫ ابقى ساكنا للحظة ♫
♫ Don't spill the wine ♫
♫ لا تسكب النبيذ ♫
♫ I can see it all from here ♫
♫ بامكاني رؤية كل ذلك من مكاني ♫
♫ I can see ♫
♫ استطيع ان ارى ♫
♫ oh, I ♫
♫ نعم , نعم ♫
♫ weather systems of the world ♫
♫ انظمة الطقس الخاصة بالعالم ♫
♫ Weather systems ♫
♫ انظمة الطقس ♫
♫ of the world ♫
♫ الخاصة بالعالم ♫
Thanks.
شكرا.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)